Steen, Ivan; Papers apap219
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Ivan Steen Papers
1928-2013
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Steen, Ivan D., 1936-
apap219
5.29 cubic ft.
The Ivan Steen Papers document Steen's service as a Professor of History at the University at Albany as well as his oral history projects.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted with the exception of several folders marked below. While Ivan Steen subsequently asked individuals interviewed for the oral history projects he conducted to sign a clearance form or an agreement, not all interview files donated to the archive contain forms. Therefore notes, transcripts and audio of a select number of interviews are restricted until clearance may be obtained from the interviewees or their heirs.
Acquisition Information
Ivan Steen donated his papers to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives in a series of acquisitions in 2005, 2007, 2012, 2013, 2015, 2016, and 2017.
Biographical Sketch
Ivan D. Steen was a long time professor at the University at Albany. He began his career at Hunter College of the City University of New York after completing his schooling at New York University, where he received his bachelor’s, master’s, and doctoral degrees. After three years on the faculty at Hunter College, Steen joined the University at Albany's History Department in 1965 as an assistant professor. He became founding director of the University's Public History Graduate Program in 1983, an associate professor in 1985 and associate professor emeritus in 2010. He also served as Vincent O’Leary Associate Professor of History from 2010-2013. During his tenure at the University at Albany, Steen published numerous articles and essays, attended and spoke at academic conferences, lectures, and panels across the country and internationally, and hosted workshops. He was a member of the University Senate as well as a member of United University Professions (UUP). He was elected vice president and president of UUP's Albany chapter during the 1990s and early 2000s. Steen continues to co-direct the Center for Applied Historical Research at the University.
Professor Steen is passionate about oral history and local history. As founding director of the University's Oral History Program, Steen’s projects often focused on a combination of the two. Two of Steen’s major projects were the Erastus Corning Years Oral History Project and The Rockefeller Years: An Oral History of the State of New York Under Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller. Steen, along with students in the program, worked on other projects pertaining to local history such as Albany’s black community, the history of the Fort Orange Club, local area Holocaust survivors, and memories of radio personnel. Steen personally conducted many interviews as did his research associates and students in the Oral History Program. Records of these projects are found in Series 1 along with materials relating to Steen's research of former Prisoners of War (POW) from World War I, World War II, the Korean War, and the Vietnam War.
In 2013 Steen officially retired from his positions at the University at Albany.
Scope and Contents
The Ivan Steen Papers document his work at the University at Albany, including his numerous oral history projects, research conducted for the projects, and his time as an associate professor of History, founding director of the Oral History Program and founding director of the Public History Graduate Program. This collection is divided into two series. The first series, Oral History and Research Files, is arranged alphabetically while the second series, University at Albany History Department, is arranged chronologically.
The Oral History and Research Files series contains audio cassette tapes, transcripts, notes and related correspondence of the interviews conducted by Steen, his colleagues, and his students. Steen's research materials for his multiple oral history projects are housed in this series as well. Researchers should note that material pertaining to the Public History and Oral History Programs are found within the first series, as these programs often produced the work found in said series. Steen’s History Department records, which include memorandum, meeting minutes, correspondence, and reports are retained in Series 2.
Researchers should note that some materials Professor Steen donated were moved to separate collections because he created these records as a member or officer of an organization and not as an individual. Therefore, archivists transferred material pertaining to UUP and the University Senate to their respective collections. Archivists also transferred records to the UUP Oral History Collection. These collections are all found in this department.
For related material, please see the Brothers Records, Daniel Evan Button Papers, Dolores Carrara Papers, Victor A. Lord Papers, Harold Rubin Papers and Malcolm Wilson Papers.
Separated Materials
The archivist transferred two monographs: Whispers of Death by Forrest W. Howell and American ex-prisoners of war: non solum armis edited by Gardner Hatch to the book division of Special Collections. These were catalogued and included in the University Library Catalog.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into the following series:
Series 1 - Oral History and Research Files, 1936, 1959-2013 Undated
Series 2 - University at Albany History Department, 1965-2013, Undated
Series 1 is arranged alphabetically and Series 2 is arranged chronologically.
African Americans and Civil Rights Organizations; Radio and Television Broadcasting; Military and Armed Conflict; Albany, New York; Oral history--New York (State); Education, Higher--New York (State); New York (State)--Politics and government; Audio cassettes; Interviews; Transcripts; Articles; Memorandums; Steen, Ivan D., 1936-; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich), 1908-1979; Corning, Erastus, 1909-1983; State University of New York at Albany; New York (State). Governor (1959-1973: Rockefeller)
- Oral History and Research Files, 1936-2012; Undated; 1; 3.89 cubic ft.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  Series 1 contains material related to Professor Steen's oral history projects and their related material. Two of his major oral history projects were about Albany Mayor Erastus Corning 2nd and New York Governor Nelson Rockefeller. Other projects pertain to topics such as Albany's black community, the Holocaust, and radio. Please note that formal oral history interviews with prisoners of war were never conducted because grant funding could not be obtained. Folders typically contain correspondence with each interviewee as well as interview transcripts and background information. There are cassette tapes to accompany the interview transcripts. Cassette tapes with general dates or date ranges indicate multiple interview dates.
  - Albany Black Community, Art Mitchell, 1984; Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Albany Black Community, Interview with Art Mitchell (1 of 2), 1984 April 18 (Cassette 1)
  - Albany Black Community, Interview with Art Mitchell (2 of 2), 1984 April 18 (Cassette 2)
  - Albany Black Community, Black History in Albany and New York State, 1966; Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Albany Black Community, Mrs. Charles Van Vranken, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Albany Black Community, Clarence Parker, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Albany Black Community, Interview with Clarence Parker (1 of 2), 1984 April 30 (Cassette 3)
  - Albany Black Community, Interview with Clarence Parker (2 of 2), 1984 April 30 (Cassette 4)
  - Albany Black Community, Interview with Gordon VanNess, Undated (Cassette 171)
  - Albany Black Community, Harriet Gibbons, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Albany Black Community, Interview with Harriet Gibbons, ca. 1984 (Cassette 5)
  - Albany Black Community, Harry Hamilton, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Albany Black Community, Laurence Burwell, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Albany Black Community, Interview with Lawrence Burwell (1 of 3), 1984 May 02 (Cassette 8)
  - Albany Black Community, Interview with Lawrence Burwell (2 of 3), 1984 May 02 (Cassette 7)
  - Albany Black Community, Interview with Lawrence Burwell (3 of 3), 1984 May 02 (Cassette 8)
  - Albany Black Community, Leon Van Dyke, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Albany Black Community, Interview with Leon Van Dyke, [RESTRICTED], 1984 April 30 (Cassette 9)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Must consult archivist before viewing this material.
  - Albany Black Community, Michael Nardolillo, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Albany Black Community, Interview with Michael Nardolillo (1 of 2), 1984 April 25 (Cassette 10)
  - Albany Black Community, Interview with Michael Nardolillo (2 of 2), 1984 April 25 (Cassette 11)
  - Albany Black Community, Nell Stokes Holmes, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Albany Black Community, Interview with Nell Stokes Holmes (1 of 2), 1984 May 04 (Cassette 12)
  - Albany Black Community, Interview with Nell Stokes Holmes (2 of 2), 1984 May 04 (Cassette 13)
  - Albany Black Community, NEH Grant Back Up Materials, 1984; 1986; Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Albany Black Community, NEH Grant Correspondence and Material, 1983-1984; Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Albany Black Community, NEH Grant Instructions and Preliminary Application, 1983; Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Albany Black Community, Notes, Reception Agenda, Statement of Purpose, 1984; Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Albany Black Community, Reverend Robert Dixon, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Albany Black Community, Interview with Reverend Robert Dixon, [RESTRICTED] (1 of 2), 1984 April 19 (Cassette 14)
  - Albany Black Community, Interview with Reverend Robert Dixon, [RESTRICTED] (2 of 2), 1984 April 19 (Cassette 15)
  - Albany Black Community, Interview with Ruby Hughes, 1984 May 16 (Cassette 170)
  - Albany Black Community, Teaching Instructions, Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Albany Democratic Party and Election Results, 1981; 1987; Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Anthony Metzner Memoirs, Correspondence, Forms, and Transcripts, 1985; 1995 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Interviews with Anthony Metzner (1 of 4), 1985 (Cassette 16)
  - Copy of Interviews with Anthony Metzner (2 of 4), 1985 (Cassette 17)
  - Interviews with Anthony Metzner (3 of 4), 1985 (Cassette 18)
  - Copy of Interviews with Anthony Metzner (4 of 4), 1985 (Cassette 19)
  - Articles about O'Connell and the Political Machine (1 of 2), 1961-1977; Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Articles about O'Connell and the Political Machine (2 of 2), 1961-1977; Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Button and Herzog Primary Race, News Articles, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Collins, Evan R. Collins Interview, [RESTRICTED], 1984 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Collins, Interview with Evan R. Collins, [RESTRICTED], 1984 March 19 (Cassette 36)
  - Corning, Arnold Proskin Interview, Correspondence, and Background Information, 1986-1987; Undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Corning, Interview with Arnold Proskin (1 of 2), 1984 January 26 (Cassette 20)
  - Corning, Interview with Arnold Proskin (2 of 2), 1984 January 26 (Cassette 21)
  - Corning, Bishop Howard Hubbard Interview and Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Corning, Interview with Bishop Howard Hubbard (1 of 2), 1987 November 10 (Cassette 22)
  - Corning, Interview with Bishop Howard Hubbard (2 of 2), 1987 November 10 (Cassette 23)
  - Corning, Comments on and Review of P. Grondahl's Mayor Erastus Corning, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Corning, Correspondence from Erastus Corning III, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Corning, Correspondence of Edwin Corning Sent to Ivan Steen, Undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Corning, Daniel Button Interviews (1 of 2), 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Corning, Daniel Button Interviews (2 of 2), 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Corning, Interviews with Daniel Button (1 of 9), 1983-1984 (Cassette 24)
  - Corning, Interviews with Daniel Button (2 of 9), 1983-1984 (Cassette 25)
  - Corning, Interviews with Daniel Button (3 of 9), 1983-1984 (Cassette 26)
  - Corning, Interviews with Daniel Button (4 of 9), 1983-1984 (Cassette 27)
  - Corning, Interviews with Daniel Button (5 of 9), 1983-1984 (Cassette 28)
  - Corning, Interviews with Daniel Button (6 of 9), 1983-1984 (Cassette 29)
  - Corning, Interviews with Daniel Button (7 of 9), 1983-1984 (Cassette 30)
  - Corning, Interviews with Daniel Button (8 of 9), 1983-1984 (Cassette 31)
  - Corning, Interviews with Daniel Button (9 of 9), 1983-1984 (Cassette 32)
  - Corning, Death and Project Review, 1983; 1985; 1999; 2003 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Corning, Dorothea Noonan Correspondence and Articles, 1987; 1995; 2005 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Corning, Douglas Brown Correspondence, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Corning, Erastus Corning Assembly Biography, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Corning, Erastus Corning 2nd, Articles, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Corning, Erastus Corning 2nd, Interview, Tape Indexes, Correspondence and Background Information, 1982-1987 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Corning, Interview with Erastus Corning 2nd (1 of 2), August 11 1982 (Cassette 33)
  - Corning, Interview with Erastus Corning 2nd (2 of 2), August 11 1982 (Cassette 34)
  - Corning, The Erastus Corning Years Oral History Project, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Corning, Erastus Corning 2nd: Seminars in Local History, Albany Institute of History and Art, 1979 December 08 (Cassette 35)
  - Corning, Francis Bergan, Correspondence and Interview (1 of 2), 1983-1991; 1993; 1998; Undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Corning, Francis Bergan, Correspondence and Interview (2 of 2), 1983-1991; 1993; 1998; Undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Corning, Interviews with Francis Bergan (1 of 13), 1984-1989 (Cassette 37)
  - Corning, Interviews with Francis Bergan (2 of 13), 1984-1989 (Cassette 38)
  - Corning, Interviews with Francis Bergan (3 of 13), 1984-1989 (Cassette 39)
  - Corning, Interviews with Francis Bergan (4 of 13), 1984-1989 (Cassette 40)
  - Corning, Interviews with Francis Bergan (5 of 13), 1984-1989 (Cassette 41)
  - Corning, Interviews with Francis Bergan (6 of 13), 1984-1989 (Cassette 42)
  - Corning, Interviews with Francis Bergan (7 of 13), 1984-1989 (Cassette 43)
  - Corning, Interviews with Francis Bergan (8 of 13), 1984-1989 (Cassette 44)
  - Corning, Interviews with Francis Bergan (9 of 13), 1984-1989 (Cassette 45)
  - Corning, Interviews with Francis Bergan (10 of 13), 1984-1989 (Cassette 46)
  - Corning, Interviews with Francis Bergan (11 of 13), 1984-1989 (Cassette 47)
  - Corning, Interviews with Francis Bergan (12 of 13), 1984-1989 (Cassette 48)
  - Corning, Interviews with Francis Bergan (13 of 13), 1984-1989 (Cassette 49)
  - Corning, The Groton School Yearbook, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Corning, Harold Rubin Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Corning, Harold Segal Interviews, 1987-1990 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Corning, Interviews with Harold Segal (1 of 8), 1987-1988 (Cassette 50)
  - Corning, Interviews with Harold Segal (2 of 8), 1987-1988 (Cassette 51)
  - Corning, Interviews with Harold Segal (3 of 8), 1987-1988 (Cassette 52)
  - Corning, Interviews with Harold Segal (4 of 8), 1987-1988 (Cassette 53)
  - Corning, Interviews with Harold Segal (5 of 8), 1987-1988 (Cassette 54)
  - Corning, Interviews with Harold Segal (6 of 8), 1987-1988 (Cassette 55)
  - Corning, Interviews with Harold Segal (7 of 8), 1987-1988 (Cassette 56)
  - Corning, Interviews with Harold Segal (8 of 8), 1987-1988 (Cassette 57)
  - Corning, Hit or Miss: Property Tax Assessment Practices in the City of Albany, a NYPIRG Report, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Corning, Hudson Valley Survey Comm. - Reports, 1938-1940 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Corning, Human Subject Review, 1982-1999; Undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Corning, Information about the Project and Interviews Conducted, Undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Corning, Interviews by Rockefeller College Student John Piezak, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Corning, James Gallagher Interview, 1984; 1988 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Corning, Interviews with James Gallagher (1 of 9), 1984-1985 (Cassette 58)
  - Corning, Interviews with James Gallagher (2 of 9), 1984-1985 (Cassette 59)
  - Corning, Interviews with James Gallagher (3 of 9), 1984-1985 (Cassette 60)
  - Corning, Interviews with James Gallagher (4 of 9), 1984-1985 (Cassette 61)
  - Corning, Interviews with James Gallagher (5 of 9), 1984-1985 (Cassette 62)
  - Corning, Interviews with James Gallagher (6 of 9), 1984-1985 (Cassette 63)
  - Corning, Interviews with James Gallagher (7 of 9), 1984-1985 (Cassette 64)
  - Corning, Interviews with James Gallagher (8 of 9), 1984-1985 (Cassette 65)
  - Corning, Interviews with James Gallagher (9 of 9), 1984-1985 (Cassette 66)
  - Corning, James T. Foley Interview, Correspondence, and Articles, 1986-1988; 1990; Undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Corning, Interviews with James T. Foley (1 of 4), 1986-1987 (Cassette 67)
  - Corning, Interviews with James T. Foley (2 of 4), 1986-1987 (Cassette 68)
  - Corning, Interviews with James T. Foley (3 of 4), 1986-1987 (Cassette 69)
  - Corning, Interviews with James T. Foley (4 of 4), 1986-1987 (Cassette 70)
  - Corning, John Cross Interview, [RESTRICTED], 1984 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Corning, Interview with John Cross, [RESTRICTED], 1984 March 15 (Cassette 71)
  - Corning, Joseph Yavoditte, Correspondence with his Family, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Corning, Lewis Swyer Correspondence and Newsclippings, 1981-1988 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Corning, "A Look at Property Assessment and Public Housing in a Machine Controlled City," by Jamie Riedel, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Corning, Michael Bergan Correspondence about Francis Bergan Interviews, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Corning, Nature, 1964; 1983 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Corning, NYS Assembly Standing Committees, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Corning, NYS Senate Committees, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Corning, Newspaper Clippings for the Project, 1982-1987 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Corning Papers, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Corning, Photograph of Erastus Corning 2nd, Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Corning, Project Background Information, 1986; Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Corning, Richard Conners Interviews, Articles, and Correspondence, 1960; 1966; 1983-1995 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Corning, Interviews with Richard Conners (1 of 5), 1986-1987 (Cassette 72)
  - Corning, Interviews with Richard Conners (2 of 5), 1986-1987 (Cassette 73)
  - Corning, Interviews with Richard Conners (3 of 5), 1986-1987 (Cassette 74)
  - Corning, Interviews with Richard Conners (4 of 5), 1986-1987 (Cassette 75)
  - Corning, Interviews with Richard Conners (5 of 5), 1986-1987 (Cassette 76)
  - Corning, William Hennessy Correspondence, Article, and "Hats Off Dinner", 1983; 1985; 1987 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Corning, William Thompson Jr. Interview and Correspondence, 1990; 1992 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Corning, Interview with William Thompson Jr. (1 of 2), 1990 October 10 (Cassette 77)
  - Corning, Interview with William Thompson Jr. (2 of 2), 1990 October 10 (Cassette 78)
  - Corning and Rockefeller, Joseph McGovern Correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Daniel Button, Articles, 1966-1968; 1987 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Democratic State Committee, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Diagram of Senate Chamber, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - The Downfall of the Barnes Machine, Student Paper, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - File from Rockefeller Cabinet Member Neal Moylan, 1968-1974 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Fort Orange, Correspondence, Human Subject Review and Agreement, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - General W. Reynolds Carr Interview, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Interviews with General W. Reynolds Carr (1 of 4), 1993 (Cassette 79)
  - Interviews with General W. Reynolds Carr (2 of 4), 1993 (Cassette 80)
  - Interviews with General W. Reynolds Carr (3 of 4), 1993 (Cassette 81)
  - Interviews with General W. Reynolds Carr (4 of 4), 1993 (Cassette 82)
  - George Harder, Interviews and Background Information (1 of 2), 1961-1967; 1983-1984; Undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - George Harder, Interviews and Background Information (2 of 2), 1961-1967; 1983-1984; Undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Interviews with George Harder (1 of 9), 1984 (Cassette 83)
  - Interviews with George Harder (2 of 9), 1984 (Cassette 84)
  - Interviews with George Harder (3 of 9), 1984 (Cassette 85)
  - Interviews with George Harder (4 of 9), 1984 (Cassette 86)
  - Interviews with George Harder (5 of 9), 1984 (Cassette 87)
  - Interviews with George Harder (6 of 9), 1984 (Cassette 88)
  - Interviews with George Harder (7 of 9), 1984 (Cassette 89)
  - Interviews with George Harder (8 of 9), 1984 (Cassette 90)
  - Interviews with George Harder (9 of 9), 1984 (Cassette 91)
  - Harold Koreman Background Information, Undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - History of the Albany Common Council Project, Nancy Burton and Stephen McArdle Jr, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Holocaust Project, Article, Background Information, Notes, and Interview Transcripts, [RESTRICTED], 1978; 1983; Undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Holocaust Project, Correspondence, Human Subject Review, 1983-1984; Undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Holocaust Project, Interviews with Imac Metzger, [RESTRICTED] (1 of 2), 1984 (Cassette 92)
  - Holocaust Project, Interviews with Imac Metzger, [RESTRICTED] (2 of 2), 1984 (Cassette 93)
  - Holocaust Project, Interviews with Lila Klein, [RESTRICTED] (1 of 6), 1983 (Cassette 94)
  - Holocaust Project, Interviews with Lila Klein, [RESTRICTED] (2 of 6), 1983 (Cassette 95)
  - Holocaust Project, Interviews with Lila Klein, [RESTRICTED] (3 of 6), 1983 (Cassette 96)
  - Holocaust Project, Interviews with Lila Klein, [RESTRICTED] (4 of 6), 1983 (Cassette 97)
  - Holocaust Project, Interviews with Lila Klein, [RESTRICTED] (5 of 6), 1983 (Cassette 98)
  - Holocaust Project, Interviews with Lila Klein, [RESTRICTED] (6 of 6), 1983 (Cassette 99)
  - Holocaust Project, Interviews with Murray Jaros (1 of 4), 1983 (Cassette 100)
  - Holocaust Project, Interviews with Murray Jaros (2 of 4), 1983 (Cassette 101)
  - Holocaust Project, Interviews with Murray Jaros (3 of 4), 1983 (Cassette 102)
  - Holocaust Project, Interviews with Murray Jaros (4 of 4), 1983 (Cassette 103)
  - Map of New York State Showing Number of Members of Assembly, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Map of New York State Showing Senatorial Districts, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Members of N.Y.S. Assembly, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Memoir of Colonel Armand Hobins, 1982; 1988 (Oversized 1)
  - Michael McNulty Background Information, Undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - The Monaghen Investigation, Student Paper, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - New York State Assembly Members, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - "The New York Crystal Palace Exhibition," Steen's Master's Thesis, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - New York State Joint Legislative Committee, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - NY State Constitutional Convention, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - NY State Assembly Committees, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Oral History Program, Correspondence, 1982-1983; 1993; 1996 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Oral History Program, Fundraising, 1982-1986 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Oral History Program, Project Proposals, 1984; 1995 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - POW, A Modern Day Tragedy, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - POW, American Ex-POWs Inc. Information, 1985; Undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - POW, American Ex-POWs Inc. National Medial Research Committee Packets 8-10, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - POW, Correspondence and Newsclippings, 1987-1991 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - POW Courage Personified by Lysle Lewis, ca. 1988 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - POW, "Death March" Article, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - POW, History of Baatan Relief Organization, Bataan Veterans Organization, and History of American Ex-POW, 1972-1989 (Box 2, Folder 41)